# SAAHITH HEGDE

(214) 870-2704 | saahithhegde97@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/saahithhegde

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:**

Technically savvy software engineer with focus on Full Stack Development. Solid experience in Web Application development using modern technology stacks; Very strong in Frameworks such as Spring Boot, .Net and Angular. Experience in cloud technologies such as AWS.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

#### Instructor- Computer Science Outreach Program-University of Texas at Dallas

Mar 2020-Present

- Instructor for Full Stack Web Development Classes for over 50 students.
- Conducted 4 workshops as part of the outreach program.

#### SWE (Full Stack) - Univva Business Solutions Pvt Ltd - Bangalore, India.

Sept 2017-Jan 2019

- Architected, designed and developed the core engines of USCAN, a web application that provided smart customer analytics solutions which
  enabled quick decisions based on actionable insights, improved operations, customer services and risk management.
- Utilized Angular and .NET stack. The outcome of this project improved the sales by 2x and reduced operations time by 70 percent.
- The core engines of the product crawled data from automotive portals and performed analytics. The crawlers were designed to be 60% dynamic to changes on the website and used least amount of server resources.
- Worked on implementing ingestion service to push data into the database; Defined data models, performed data mapping, wrote Wrapper Classes and queries using MongoDB.
- Worked on front end dashboards that displayed customized results in the form of charts and graphs using angular framework.

#### **OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS:**

#### **Twitter Sentiment Analysis:**

March 2020 - May 2020

• Developed an **ELK stack** application that crawled 0.5 million live tweets, streamed through **Kafka** and analyzed through **Spark Streaming** and **Stanford-Core-NLP**, the data was pushed to **Elastic Search** and results were displayed using **Kibana** under 15 seconds.

#### NLP-Information Extraction:

March 2020 - May 2020

- Architected, designed and developed an NLP pipeline to extract information into templates from general wikipedia articles using AllenNLP ,Spacy ,NLTK ,TensorFlow ,Pytorch and StanfordNLP.
- The model took 1 minute to obtain valuable data and was 90% accurate.

#### Stockbroker Application:

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

- Architected, designed and developed a Full Stack application that provides users with an easy way to buy and sell stocks. The application
  was developed using Angular 8, Spring Boot, Hibernate, RabbitMQ and MySQL.
- The application also provided Reliability using queuing, Fast page load times using caching and compression, SSO, scheduling of stocks, adding bank accounts, wallet options and security at different levels.

#### **Recommendation of Location Specific Crop:**

Aug 2018 - April 2019

- Architected, designed and developed an application to predict and recommend a location specific crop using Python,
   Pandas ,TensorFlow ,ANN (Relu function) ,Decision Tree ,Cluster Analysis and Flask.
- The application used climate, rainfall pattern and soil profile data provided by the National Bureau of Soil Survey and Land Use Planning.
- Accuracy of models were close to 92 percent and models were generated under 30 minutes.

#### Resnal:

Feb 2018 - April 2019

- Architected, designed and developed a Full Stack application to crawl 0.1 million student grades from the university website and performed analysis on the data to provide various insights into students, class and college performance.
- The application utilized Beautiful Soup4, PythonOCR, Angular Framework, ChartJS and Django.
- This application enabled teachers and professors an easy and quick way to evaluate individual students and entire classes.

#### **Registration Scanner:**

April 2019

- Architected, designed and developed an Android application which enabled image capture, processing and OCR of vehicle registration cards.
- The application provided details of the owner, checked for validity, authenticity and traffic violations on the registration numbers.
- The application utilized **Rekognition**, **S3**, **EC2 AWS services**. The pipeline took 5 seconds with 85% accuracy.

## SKILLS:

Languages: Java, Python, C#, C, PHP, SQL, JavaScript.

Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate, .NET, Flask, Angular, jQuery, AJAX, Hadoop, Spark, Spark-Streaming, Android.

Other Technologies: Spacy, TensorFlow, NLTK, Git, AWS, Stanford-Core-NLP, Kafka, Firebase, mongoDB.

### **EDUCATION:**

• MS in Computer Science, University of Texas at Dallas ,USA

GPA:3.89; Expected Graduation-May 2021

• BS in Computer Science and Engineering, Visvesvaraya Technological University, India

GPA:3.8; 2019

## **CERTIFICATIONS:**

- AWS Udemy Certified Developer Associate 2020
- Spring Framework for Beginners with Spring Boot Udemy